(♪ twinkling, string music ♪)
(toddler talk)
Uh, we don't getTV in this house,
um, we all havecomputers.
My daughter and my sonare three and two
and they each havetheir own computers,
and they're lined up nextto mommy's computers,
and um, my little girl isreally really super smart.
She can use acomputer really well,
she surfs around this, onlineand she uses photoshop
she uses word, I meanshe's only three years old
and she can read andwrite and use a computer
just like an adult,she's pretty amazing.
I didn't planto be a single mom.
I didn't plan to be stuckin the middle of the desert
where I don'tknow anybody,
it's just kind of allbeen thrown for a loop.
(gun shots)
So at that pointI said we gotta arrest him,
so we arrested him, and hecried like a baby, didn't he.
"I can't go back to jail!Ahhhhhhhh!"
and he justcried like a baby.
I said okay.
I gave him the opportunityto make very small
reasonable payments, he didn'tmake any of the payments,
I warned him if he didn'tmake the payments
I was gonna comeand take his grandma's car.
That's what he forced usto do, and the day that
I took this car his little87-year-old grandma
or mother was outthere with her walker
watching ustake her car.
And it was oneof the hardest things
I've ever had to dobut you know what?
Business isbusiness.
(gun shot)
So. Now the clay ispretty much conditioned,
it's readyto be worked with.
We're gonna giveourselves, a base,
and then uh, he willbe put into action.
I would see if hecan find a girlfriend.
Since he's gone throughout thisradical surgicalprocedure,
to have his penisre-installed.
Imagine how happy he iswhen he wakes up
and finds out,he's got a dick again.
Wow, you knowthat's a,
that's a big dayin the coyote's life.
Huh?!
And I knew that,getting this opportunity to be
on a mainstream show,I knew my whole life,
like, once I got out to LA,once I could get on a
reality show, and get theopportunity to show people,
like, about me, that thatwould be the big thing
I need to moveforward mainstream.
I just need that oneopportunity to get there.
No! What happens isit like, it like,
like, you're tryingto put it in it like bends.
And you, it's betterif it's like a solid one.
That's realityright there.
No, I'm not kidding.
But, like, one like this, thenit doesn't, it goes faster.
(laughing)
And he comes from,of course the uh,
story of the old testament,the story of Josean.
Um, and this is kind of amodern day adaptation ofthat.
(unintelligibleconversation)
That is amazing,
that is amazing and Godbless you and take care.
I'm definitely stillgrowing spiritually.
I don't think youcan ever quit growing.
There's always roomto get closer to God
and things to learnabout him and...
ways to change yourlife and to improve.
It is a mess.
You're a mess.
It's a mess.
(laughing)
But that's the waygnocchis are.
A little bit of a mess.
It's like, a guy told me once,when he was painting.
Is that how you, how it was morebasic and then he went in.
Well it wasn't more basic,it was just a painting I did
and then one day I tookit out and I just
started painting all thisother stuff in there
and just went inwith this reds and...
I don't, I don't rememberwhat it looked like before,
I can't remember,I just, very hard to keep
a band togetherand I only wanna play
with certain guys thatI really love playing with.
Cause it allcomes together,
it's like summertheatre you know.
Wow!
I got a barn,and I got to, I got to ,
I got the instruments,we'll put our own show on!
You knowwhat I mean.
It all still has that,that element.
This is uh, oneof the Chinatown series.
From my home town.After the mill closed.
I mean,pretty much closed.
What'd you get last year,
for your birthday,from Aunt Lynny?
I thinka Power Ranger suit.
You got what?No, you didn't!
You didn't get a Power Rangersuit that was for Halloween.
You got anelectric guitar--
A 'lectric guitar--
A REAL electric guitar!
Why? Because you toldaunt Lynny you wanted
to grow upto be a rockstar.
You know what, I justsee a beautiful girl
and I justwanna hug her!
(laughing)
Well, I love this one righthere, so I telling you.
I currently reach outto women and men
in the sex industryand the porn industry
and I absolutely lovepulling them out of the pit
the porn industry pit.
It's 1800 square feetand, the guest house is
around 600square feet.
That little garage area,I don't know.
Um, it took me about a yearto really get serious
about studying, and,it took me three times
to pass the testbut I did it and,
(deep breath),here I am.
(laughing)
Got into real-estate,
I've been in itfor five years.
Yup.
Dark and mild.
No, he likesthe dark heavy.
Dark heavy.
When I'm at home, I runaround with no makeup on,
a pair of sweatpants,bare foot, a t-shirt,
and I'm usually outin the yard digging.
Because I liketo plant things,
I like to grow things.Or decorating my house.
I like to do crafty things,like, you know, I don't,
I know I don't seem likethe domestic goddess!
But I, I, I like to makethings for the house
and I love to cook.And, I'm a very good cook.
I had a little bit,of, a, some bad terrible
terrible news,uh, this April.
Um, I was diagnosed with uh,stage three melanoma cancer.
So for the pastfour or five months
I've been dealingwith that and on chemo.
They recommended completedissection of thelymph-nodes,
and then to be onheavy-dose interferon,
which would beuh, intravenous,
which I would getfive times a week,
for the first month,and then after that,
three times a week,for eleven months,
for the restof the year.
And um, it's,it's been tough.
It's actuallygreat here, cause,
how many porno starslive here? I know--
There'ssome more uh,
there's some morecoming in uh, Sunset,
uh, Houston, uh, TaylorSaint-Claire just moved here.
What, whateverhappened to uh,
she was reallyhot, but I loved her.
What happenedto that um...
oh godammit, I don'tknow their names
I'm really badwith this, um--
You remembertheir tits. Yeah.
Oh god, she was um, oh thatdoesn't make any difference.
She was living here fora long time she was so hot.
(unintelligibleconversation)
Oh yeah, she justmoved outta town,
yeah, she justmoved outta town.
And uh, that's the only thingI missed out on in life.
I've done, prettymuch everything I wanted.
I did wanna have kids,didn't have the opportunity
to meet the right womanthe right time,
so I do kindamiss out on that,
but uh, nobody gets everythingthere's other guys
that have great kids and theylove every minute of it
they kinda wish theywere me, fantasy wise,
but um, nobodygets everything.
♪
I started modelingin ninth grade.
My mom put methrough modeling school,
I graduatedfrom modeling school,
started doingbeauty pageants,
and model searches,and bikini contests.
So, I was exposed, to,not so much the adult industry
but just knowing that I couldmake money with my body.
I had a roommateat the time,
um, that was a dancer,and she knew an agent,
his name wasJim Salf.
He said, "Hey, there's aproducer that saw yourpicture
and he'd like youto come do a movie
how would you liketo do a movie?"
And I said, uh, well,I've never done a movie before
but sure, I coulddo it, no problem.
I went down and I hadbraids like Bo Derek
at the time and,did my first scene.
It was a three-way.
I had never even,been with a woman,
I didn't know whatto do with a woman,
I had, no ideawhat I was doing.
But the minutethose lights hit me,
I swear that was whereI was supposed to be.
Everyone said doit, do it, do it.
And the more you do themore money you can make
dancing on the dance circuit,the more magazines you cando,
the more you'reexposed, you can,
I mean gosh,I have a sex toy line,
now we wanna doan action figure of you.
Okay!
I mean, all of itwas just like, cool!
You know,sign me up! Sure!
I was just having a blast,I mean, there were fans
lined up for miles andmiles and miles that flew,
I mean some people camefrom Poland and Berlin,
and come to think of itwhen I went to Poland,
to um, signautographs and whatever,
I mean, when I got off theplane I needed a body guard!
I mean, for a porn star to bethat big, around the world,
I mean, it was un-believable,I mean felt like a--
I was a true super star!
I mean people, wereknocking each other down.
Heeeere's Houston!!!!
(cheering)
Over the Dali Lamain the newspaper,
I was the headliner.I mean, that's unbelievable.
I was still under contract,I was with Metro Productions
for a few years, and they'rethe ones that also produced
uh, the Houston 500, theworld's biggest gang-bang.
Um, at that point when Ifirst signed with Metro,
it was already known going inthat I was gonnatakeover,
uh, Jasmine Saint-Clair'stitle and do this gang-bang.
So, going into mycontract with Metro,
I already knew that Iwas gonna be doing that,
so, I wasn't, I wasn'tlooking for things to,
oh I've gotta bemore crazy and wild,
you know honestly it justall came to me naturally.
Like, I mean,I had a labiaplasty,
and that was before alot of women even knew
that they can gettheir labia trimmed
if you have larger labialips and you know,
when I did that it was like,oh, it was just a no brainer
I'm gonna encase that inlucite and auction it.
The trimmings.
I mean, it's justthings just came to me,
I was just apublicity whore.
I was good at it.
I had invested mymoney, uh, I bought a home,
as well as, um, put a lotof money in mutual funds,
and many years ago whenthe stock market went kaput,
I lost, like,almost all my savings.
And that hurt me.
Um, but I did still have myhouse that I owned in LA,
um, and then when things gotrough of course I sold it,
not for financial reasonsbut when I wanted
to get outof the industry.
I'm professor ofcommunications studies
and psychology at UCLA.
I study a variety of topics,but one of the major areas
that I study ispornography.
I'm Faith, and since 1984I've done about 600 films.
About a thousandscenes, give or take.
Um, I've won severaldozen awards for acting
in sex performances and fanfavorite and this and that.
I think it might be up, thisyear for best non-sex role
cause I've also moved into theoccasional character part
that doesn't involvehaving sex.
I write about the sexindustry pretty much
from the fall of 1995until the fall of 2007.
"The History of X: OneHundred Years of Sex inFilm"
is the nameof my first book.
I've been in the adultentertainment industry
for basically 35, 36years, in every capacity.
I started as awriter, became an actor,
director, agent, and nowI'm sorta the, papa bear
to the adult entertainmentindustry, protecting
adult welfare, which I run,and, watch over the overaged
juvenile delinquentsand what I refer to as
the playpen of the damned,which is the X-ratedindustry.
What we give them in theadult entertainment industry
for a brief shinymoment is immortality,
validation, and credibility.
Every one of us, nomatter how insignificant
we may think we are,wants to be recognized
at one time or anotherin our lives,
and when you went to thoseconventions they lined up
at your booth like theywere getting signatures
from professionalathletes.
My parents divorced.My dad took us far away
from our mother, andran away with us.
He becamean alcoholic.
Then I moved inwith my mom
and the familyrelationship changed, um,
I felt kind of lost.
I worked a regularjob, um, in an office,
for five years, but whileI was doing those things
I also found um,a modeling website
and I put my pictureson the website,
and then um, you know, I wasstill working in the office
but people were emailingme about doing shoots.
And I thought itwould be cool to do,
like, bikini stuff, or,even though I never really
even walked around in bikinisI thought it would be,
kind of neat.
So, eventually, I didtake a job, um doing,
um, you know theywere only asking me
to do nudes and eventuallyI just did it.
I went to my firstshoot, in like a hotel room,
and um, it was justsupposed to be topless,
and it, was, itwas really scary.
Um--
It was weird.
Well ever since I, sinceI got into the business,
I always got emails,that said that you,
you don't lookquite comfortable,
and I think that itwas the innocence,
that, attracted my,a lot of my fans,
is that I didn't look totallycomfortable in anything I did,
and even if I wasspeaking I didn't look
totally comfortable and Inever looked confident,
I wasn't very verbal,I wasn't, you know,
over the top with thenoises or anything, um.
I dunno, I just started feeling,really depressed about it.
Honestly.
And, then I hitrock bottom myself,
emotionally, where Ium, got really upset
and I'd go in the bathroomand I threw a glass
on the ground and thenI um, just crying
and fall to the groundand just started like,
pounding my wrists intothe glass, and blood was,
just started goingeverywhere, and...
I dunno, I justkinda lost that hope.
I did have a stalker,um, he started off
just sending mehate-mail.
He's an atheist, sohe was pretty much,
putting downwhat I believe in
and trying to getme to debate him.
He, heh, becameobsessed with me
and developed likethis, crush on me.
And then I told himwe would never date,
I don't know you Idon't know where you live,
you're too young,blah blah blah.
And um, he flipped out.
(nervous laughing)
The thing that pushed meto the edge
was he said he wasgonna, um, he wanted
to bash my headinto the concrete
until my brainsspilled out.
And then kill my catand stuff like that.
A few fans had emailedme the last year or so
and said they werepraying for me
and that they were notlooking at porn anymore,
and, you know, and then Ihad this other guy saying
you need to put awarning on your website
because kidscan see this
my fourteen-year-old sonfound this, and then--
Just all kinds ofpeople were like,
sending me these emails,random emails and--
You know it uh, andof course I would,
I was alwayskind of sympathetic
to whatever they saidbut, um, there was some,
you know I was stillkind of hardened too,
at the same time,because I was like well,
I can't do anything else,this is what I'm good at.
This is all that,I know.
And, I kind ofbelieved it at the time.
I didn't haveanybody you know,
saying, you'rebetter than that.
So, um...(nervous laughing)
Some adult stars do"find god" and leave,
but those arepeople who needed,
who needed to be goneanyway, and did not have
the personal strength todo it and so they do
look outside for somethingto help them leave.
Um, there are plenty ofpeople in the business
who really shouldn't behere, because they have
conflict about-- ifI was-, if I'd been raised
to be ashamed of mybody, and to feel bad
about men and their andthe horrible desires,
but, did porn for other reasonseventually those two things
are gonna co-, wheels aregonna come off the bus.
I can only deny it solong, people try to deny,
they stuff theirfeelings with, with drugs,
and alcohol, or whatever it isthey stuff their feelings with
and after a six months,one year, five year,
ten years, whatever itfinally goes you know what?
I can't do this anymore.
Because for religion andespecially western religion,
especially Christianitysays I love you,
I forgive you, youcan come home now.
And I will not push you out.
And so that is incrediblypowerful and incredibly potent
to have someone finallysay I don't shame you.
I love you.
You're welcome here.
Sign me up!
When you're involvedin this industry
you lose your humanity.
You're no longer treatedas a human being
by eighty percent ofpeople out there.
You're now, now scum.
Like they maybe wanna, docertain things with you.
But then, you're still scum.
And, like if, they maybe thrilled to have
a roll in the sac withyou but when they leave,
when you leave they'regonna wanna burn the sheets.
Uh, ah, I got intoporn by accident.
It wasn't somethingI planned on doing,
uh, probably mighta beenthe, the least likely thing
I thought I woulda done.
I was singing inbands after I,
a baseball thingdidn't work out,
uh, I knew I could sing so Istarted singing in rock bands.
And of course like allstruggling musicians
you gotta make a littleextra dough on the side.
It actually, my, my first nakedjob I was a nude artmodel
for like you know college artclasses and stuff like that.
And I was really kinda shybut not about my body
just about talking I waskinda shy about talking.
but yeah I'd get nakedin front of people
so I did that and a couplegirls in one of the classes
asked to take some picturesof me and they did and--
They came out pretty good andthey said can we send them
to some magazines I said Idon't care do what you want.
And they sent'em out andand next thing I know
I got a letter from Playgirl,and, but High Society
said they like to do a boy/girlthing but I said alright.
So it was the firstthing I ever did.
And they had a womaneditor and at the end
of the shoot she goesyou know uh,
I noticed you were taking careof business pretty good,
did you ever think aboutdoing a porn movie
cause I gotsome connections.
And I go, I never reallythought about it, no.
She goes well you know, I think,I can get you 250 bucks.
Like, 250 bucks man!
1978 that wassome good cash,
that's what Iwas making a week!
So I said uh, alrightI'll try it, you know.
So I did it and uh,guess I was good at it
cause they keptcalling me back.
And uh, that's kindahow it got started.
I, I used to say it's likeborrowing somebody's body
to masturbate with.
Uh, excuse me, if you'renot busy do you mind
if I jerk off in yourpussy with my dick?
Uh, it's kinda likethat, which it's not bad,
I mean you know, betterthan real jerkin' off, but--
When I first startedproducing up-and-comers
I get this letter in themail and I open it up
and I see this unbelievably,good-looking,
very younglooking blonde girl,
with beautifulnatural boobs,
little baby face, andshe wants to know
if I can help her getin the porn biz.
Girl's name wasJenna Jameson.
I remember saying thisI mean holy christ
if I get this girlto shoot for me
we're gonna sellsome tapes.
I said well if you don'twanna do guys you know
I'll let you pickwhatever girl you want
if you wanna do that.And she liked girls.
so she picked this girl that Ihappened to be working with
that day who was doing herfirst movie, Kylie Ireland,
so Kylie and Jenna weredoing their thing together
and uh, everything wasgoing good, and they took
a little break and whilethey were lying there I--
I think I said something like,
man Jenna that's a tastylooking pussy you got.
And I believe she said wellwhy don't you come in
and taste it.
I went--
Okay, I was doing thecamera but I handed it
to my assistant, Bob holdonto this, start shooting.
So I get in there and Istart going down on her
and she starts squealing thatlittle squeal that she had
and um, I'm guessing she'skinda liking it you know,
and seemed like she was gettingoff and everything's good
and I said man, I amso fuckin' horny now.
I said would youguys mind maybe like,
giving me a doubleblowjob or something?
And they said sure, we cando that, and I'm like--
Thank you, thank you!
And they did and it wentwell and a week later
she kinda called me backand said you know what
you weren't so bad I thinkI could probably do
a boy girl thing withyou and the rest is
kinda history after that.
Getting "It's a DaddyThing" number three!
Old man, canmake a comeback!
Yeah!
So there baby,no viagra yet!
Um, and it, you know,it's cool you do your thing,
you go home, you came,you relax you know but,
I'm kind of anaffectionate kinda guy,
and so I kinda miss thatpart of it and that's why
I still like havinga relationship,
when it happens, you know.
And uh, you know for exampleeh, Tera Patrick man,
not only wasshe incredible in bed
but there was just,I just liked her.
And, that that, sense ofhumor and the craziness,
a little bitdifferent, you know.
So, I hadn't dated anybodyin so long when I met her
I forgot howto do it, and uh,
I did ask her outto dinner twice,
and we went out to dinnerand we had a good time
but I dropped her off at herplace without asking her
if I could, come in.
And I don't knoweh, I might have,
she mightathought I was weird.
I already had sex with her acouple of times, on camera,
and she mighta thoughtit was weird that
I didn't wanna come upand finish the date,
but I was kinda showing herthat I wasn't just there
for the sex, and, maybeit wasn't a good move
cause you leave abeautiful woman like that
alone for too long and somebodyelse is gonna come along
and somebody elsedid come along and,
that was that.
She made it today,this is Tera Patrick.
Hello.
And uh, Tera is reasonablyknown in the business
and hasn't evenworked that often.
Apparently.
Um.
I was just trying topace myself right now.
One of my alltime favorites.
Most of the people who seekit out don't have means
of making that kind ofmoney by other means.
I mean very fewwomen say hmm,
I'm going to become asurgeon or I'm going
to becomea pornography star.
This country doesnot raise people
with a very good work ethic.
They don't know howto do anything else.
They don't knowhow to do retail,
they don't know how todo Excel spreadsheets.
Many people who make theirway to adult entertainment,
like rock-and-roll, are notsuited for nine-to-fivework.
I, ran away fromhome at sixteen
and was living on thestreets at seventeen.
Uh, everything I ownedwas in two garbage bags.
Um, my parents were saying Ihope you just kill yourself
and make life a loteasier for the rest of us.
Uh, it was just on and onand on so there I was
out on the streets andthen, when I got taken in
with a foster family,um, I made sure that
I kept finishing schoolwith good grades
because that was gonnabe my future that
was gonna be my ticketoutta there and then
when I went to college onfull academic scholarship
I never actuallywent to classes.
I said okay I've gotfree room and board,
I need to make money.
I need to get some sort ofsecurity and stability
in my life so I don't haveto turn tricks
to get food to eat.
So I took up stripping, I wentto all the local stripbars,
and from there I started doingmagazines in New YorkCity.
I would take a trainto New York CIty
on weekendsand do magazines.
And then, uh, a photographersaid he knew a director
in California named BudLee who could direct me
in some movies if Iwanted to do that.
So um, I packed up mysuitcase and a teddy bear
and went out to LA.
Made a movie for Bud Lee,married him, didn't come back.
The reason that Iwanted to do porn,
even though I was so smart,Miss MENSA and all that is
uh, it's precisely because Iwanted to stop being known
as the nerd the geek the,the one that you come over
and you be nice to mejust so you can copy off
of my tests, you know.
(laughing)
I would hang out with someof my misfit friends
and they had, theyhad adult magazines
hidden under their bed andthey would look at them
and I would be peekingover their shoulder going
I wish someone wouldlook at me like that.
And that was just likemy wildest fantasy that
someone would thinkthat I was pretty
and sexy and, woo!
All my life I'd justbeen the nerd and the geek.
So it was like a fantasycome true for me that
someone wanted to see meon the cover of a magazine.
When I got to porn it waslike wait, I get to pick
which one of these good-lookingguys I wanna sleep with?
And uh, you're gonnapay me for it
and then you're gonnaput me on a box cover
and give me tons of money?
(laughing)
It was just uh, areally big step up
from whereI was coming from.
Porn wasn't all that muchof a mental challenge
for me shall we say,um, standing there
and saying my silly linesjust, it didn't take up
a whole lot of myday so meanwhile
you got a lot oftime to sit around
and wait so uh, I justkept myself busy
by learning everysingle job on the set.
Um, I (laughing)I would get
the grips to take medown to the grip truck
and show me the namesof everything on there
and teach me how to doeverything by showing up
with my little grip belt andmy shorts and my gloves
and no shirt on.
(laughing)
and I would ask very nicelyif they would teach me
their job and they did,and uh,
much the same way Ilearned editing,
directing,producing, scriptwriting,
um, every job onthe set I've gotten.
If you look on IMDB my name hasgot all credits next toit
I did everything.
I even designedmy own box covers.
Um, what made me different wasI was the first half-asian
to become an A-liststar in the business.
Um, before I'd startedthere was the white girls
and the black girlsand the asian girls
and each had theirown separate genre,
and, they didn't mix,you, you don't put
an asian girl in awhite girl movie.
(laughing)
It's justthe way it was.
And then when I came inand I was only half-asian
the features were soft enoughthat they could still
put me on a cover and I couldstill be a white girl,
or and asian girl, theycould play me either way.
Or they could play meas an Indian or a Gypsy,
or, Greek girl!
They gave me allthe different roles.
So they just, theywound up using
my lookas very versatile.
And so I became thefirst "cross-over" star
from a minority, and then uh,I guess they did pretty well
with me cause after I leftVivid they got Koby Tie,
who was full asian, so,I kinda opened the door
for the minorities tobecome A-listers.
I, I hated doinglive appearance.
Oh I'm getting sweaty justlooking at this picture.
(laughing) Yeah.
I spent like all yearlong dreading the CES Show.
I would just have tokeep telling myself
they're more scaredthan you are,
they're more scaredthan you are.
Cause I'd smile and I'd say"So what's your name?"
and they'd go--(laughing)
they'd just look at me.Okay what's your name?!
If you see my very firstinterviews from when
I was nineteen,twenty years old,
I said I'm gonna retirewhen I'm thirty.
And people wouldlaugh and say
oh you've got itall planned out.
There really wasn'tany question about it.
I had, gotten married,and, then divorced.
And I met someone whohad adult bookstores.
So I basically gotmy introduction
to the adult entertainmentworld through working
in adult bookstores,and then consequently
owning adult bookstoresand I saw the women
that were doing movies atthe time and, I was just,
amazed, because, they hadpimples on their rear-ends,
they had on no makeup,their feet were dirty,
their hair was dirty,and I thought my god,
this is not a really goodrepresentation of women.
I wanna do that.
I mean I had done, um, afew magazines and a few uh,
like, 8 mm loops, andthen I came to California,
and I picked up one ofthe free papers and,
there was an ad.
My family was very, veryokay with what I did
because I did tell themwhat I was about to do
before I actuallydid anything.
I mean I'd done acouple of photo shoots,
and decided that I neededto tell my family
before it got out therebecause I didn't want
them finding outfrom someone else.
And they're likewell do, you think
you can make money at it?
You think you can have a goodcareer and be happy doing this?
And I said yes I do, andthey said good, go do it.
We had a very smallcommunity of people,
of players, thatwe all worked with.
And we all worked witheach other quite a bit.
So the community wassmall, we were familiar
with one another,and, we actu--
it's like when you, havea, a new boyfriend
or new girlfriend or anew husband or wife,
it takes a little whilebefore you know what
pushes their buttons,what turns them on
what makes them feelgood, and then it starts
to become very intimate,and, you can actually,
have an intimaterelationship with the person
you're workingwith on screen,
and be fond of themafter the movie is over.
Um, but they're justgenerally sweet nice people.
I was beingoffered parts in movies,
in, or photo shootsor what have you,
and they didn't want to payme the amount of money
I wanted, and I said no.I just, I held out.
So, um, and subsequentlyI started stripping,
going across the, basicallyacross the world stripping.
And uh, doing photo shoots withClub Magazine predominantly.
And um, so theydidn't see me in front,
people didn't see me infront of the camera
so they thought okay,she's retired.
I've been retired andcome back so many times
I can't keep track anymore.
I've also beendead a few times.
I saw an add in the paper itsaid "Nude fun, big bucks."
and uh, it was an auditionfor an X-rated movie.
Two days later I get acall from the producer,
they wanna give me apart in the movie.
I hadn't planned on that.
At the time, I had appliedto the Hebrew Union Seminary
in Cincinnati, wherethey uh, train people
to become Rabbis.
So I'm trying tomeasure, do I wanna do this,
or do I wanna be in a pornmovie because it seems
if I take the part inthe porn movie I maybe,
um, cutting some of my optionsoff, for future life.
And the uh, seminary inCincinnati said we'll take you
but the first two years youhave to go to Jerusalem
and study Aramaic, which,I would rather go
to Cleveland and studytheir sewer system.
Um,no interest there.
So I decided I wouldmake the porn movie.
And, in any case the kindof Rabbi I would become,
would be the kind thatcould've made a porn movie.
And uh, I wentahead and did the job.
I think I had to becomea sex star just
to come back to normal!
Cause I'd been so humiliatedby being the fat kid!
I had the largest breastsin the seventh grade!
The guys wouldmake fun of me
and point at meand tease me!
Do you know howdeep those scars go?!
That's ugly shit!
Those are the peoplethat become centerfolds!
Cause they gotsomething to prove.
I was lucky enough to uh, bein the era when they were
actually trying to makemovies where you needed
to remember lines.
And I had the,I was good at that.
So, I got hired formy acting ability,
which being agood actor in porn,
is like being the wisest manin the kingdom of the fools.
He promised that Icould fuck you next.
He what?!
Gah!
Ow!
(screaming)
Let him alone!
I said let him alone!
(shrieking)
Ow!Ah, oh uh!
Get the fuckoutta here!
My ankle!Ow, my ankle!
I was terribleat the sex.
Just rotten!
I was just sotraumatized by it.
But I eventually did learnhow to have sex on camera.
I was on the beach in San Diegoand uh, I was by myself.
and I'm sitting there,and I notice there's a,
really beautiful woman,laying on a towel and so
my gaze drifts over to her andher boyfriend looks at me
and sees her--and I look away.
And then eventually I'ddrift back and I'm looking
at her again and theboyfriend sees me looking
at her againand I'm like shit.
Well the guy gets up,and he starts walkin'
over towards me and I'mgoing Oh no! Here we go.
You know, this isgonna get ugly.
And he getsclose to me and I,
I'm just clenching myfist ready to defend myself.
The guy's a monster,I'm gonna get killed,
I know it, and heleans in and he says
"Were you in Insatiable?"
(laughing)And I went YES! YES!
I was so happy that's whatit was, he recognized me
from the movie businessand he wasn't gonna
kick my ass it wasa true delight.
A true delight.
We becamefriends at that point.
I hadn't told my parentsthat I was doing this.
I told them I had, wasdoing commercials
and low-budget nothing,and, well, that I,
I knew that theyweren't gonna be.
I didn't suspect theywould be very approving
of this kinda stuff.
I made the originalcall prepared
to become the blacksheep of the family.
It didn't happen.
I'm sure they wereless than thrilled.
When my mother would beat the grocery store
the next day and they say
"Good to see you,how you doing?
What's going on?"
"Well! My son the doctor's
coming back from Israel,and my other son,
he makes shmacklemovies in California!"
Well I think people mayhave a negative reaction
to someone who's a porn starfor a combination of reasons.
One is, somebody who seemsto indiscriminately
be willing to sleepwith anyone,
whether it's onfilm or not, is,
no matter what peoplesay, still not somebody
who's particularlyadmired and,
again may pose a threatto many relationships.
It is legal work,but it's fucking.
With pictures.
People say "you should,should go into politics"
There's too many pictureswith dicks in my ass,
it's like, it's notgoing to happen.
It happenedby happenstance.
I came up with some friendsand I went to a club
called The Rainbow, and, Imet there Althea Flint,
the wife of Larry Flint,and a photographer that
she had in tow, and theyapproached me and invited me
to their table, and asked meif I wanted to go to a club
and have some drinksand I did.
And she was, doing aninterview for Sting,
and we were up there lookingto meet some rockstars,
you know, wewere just girls.
Doing our thing.
And she took us in her limo,she had this black limo that
had this Think Pink onthe license plate and this,
I think it was a nakedlady on the side of it.
And I was soimpressed by that.
She said what do you doand I said I'm a model
and she said Wow!
I sh-- you know, I, Iown Hustler Magazine
and we're gonna putyou in Hustler.
So, that was that!
Um, I went into Hustler andum, started doing magazines.
My brother found out and, hehad tried to talk me into it
many times, because everybodyalways said Hey Buck!
Can you get your sisterto do a movie oh my god!
And, um, you know, wenever worked together,
on set, but, we alwayschampioned each other's careers.
And so my brother said to me,um, I want you to do a movie.
And he set it upwith Sin City,
it was actually done forSin City and it was called
Babewatch, and it was for mybrother's Babewatch series,
cause he said if you'regonna do movies for anybody,
you have to do, you haveto do one for me, sis,
so I said okay I will.
And the sex wasreal, you know,
you'd say, how doyou want the blow-job?
And he'd say, how doyou like the blowjob?
And that would beit, you know and that,
we would build offof that.
You know, I wasthe kinda person,
it, I lived alife of excess,
and people wouldinvite me to parties,
and they would think Wow!
if I offer her someparty tools, then,
I'm gonna havemy night set up,
I'm gonna wind upgetting laid all night
by this beautifulporn star.
And then as my addictionwent through another door,
they'd hand me the bagof coke and I'd wind up
in the bathroom allnight, you know,
and you wouldn't be able todrag me out of the bathroom
and I'd be likedon't touch me!
and oh!
And all of my lifestarted to kind of spiral.
I wound up getting arrested,um, on the highway,
and the police knewexactly who I was,
when I got arrested,and, they wanted
to make an example of mewith the court system.
They knew that Iwas, you know,
a big porn star, andum, the gig was up.
And I had to face it.
And it was the greatestthing that ever happened
to me when I look backon it now because,
it really broughtme into reality.
For the women, they'remuch more damned by society
because no matter howsanctified they are,
they're stillconsidered to be whores,
and it's getting worseand worse and worse
because a lot of themhave turned to,
what I am vehementlyopposed to,
the escort services, tofurther their career.
In many ways, it has adehumanizing quality,
because what you'reresponding to are a set of,
physical cues.
You areresponding to the body,
and you're responding tothe sexual acts per say
in a way that isquite animalistic.
And, having a more fulldepiction of the person
may even detract from theability to use it purely
as masturbatory or otherkind of sexual stimulation.
You can takeevery other category,
every other idea,every other thought.
Basically happiness and successin life all boils down
to what are the quality ofyour bonds with other people.
Having anything to do withthe adult industry hacks
away those bonds, so you'reisolated, alienated,
um, pushed awayto the margins,
and not treatedas a human being.
That's a recipe for disaster,for me and for anyone else.
Um, when I was in college acouple of us on the dance team
worked at Hooters so Iwas working at Hooters,
I love doing that, a lotof the girls at Hooters
were telling me how I wouldmake a lot of moneystripping
and then I had a boyfriendin college who brought me,
I went with him and his friendsto a strip club one night
because they always used togo watch amateur night.
He's like Ithink you could win,
I think you could beat thesegirls at amateur night
so I entered and I won, I gotfirst place out of twelvegirls
in the amateur contest,and I got $500.
So I was like this is a reallycool job I get to drink,
and danceand make money.
This is way better thananything else I can imagine.
When I was twenty-oneI used to watch a lot
of those cinemaX moviesand so I went to uh,
Blockbuster and I gotthe address off the box
of a cinemaX movie and Imailed some Polaroids
of myself and a a fewheadshots I had taken,
um, like, and justpictures and I mailed it
and I wrote this letter abouthow I think I'd reallylike
to be in the movies.
And I heard nothing andthen three months later
I actually got acall from Playboy.
Coming to this industry Ipretty much came into it
thinking okay I'm goingto somehow be one
of the most well-knownpornstars of all time.
I wouldn't wanna come intoit and just be another girl
that was aroundfor two years
and then have to go bea hooker. You know.
After I did the Hus-the Playboy thing,
um, I shot for Hustler, thenext month I came out to LA,
um, within three weeksafter shooting for Hustler,
um, his wife and hisdau- uh his sister,
or, his daughter, told mehow much they loved me
and they ended up taking me onthe Larry Flint Freedom Tour.
They chose four girlsto go with Larry Flint
to like different Hustlerstores on the freedom tour
and they chose me andthen Hustler had me,
my very first daybeing on the show um,
a Hustler chose me tosign at their booth,
cause they don't havecontract girls they pick girls.
And then a month later therewas a Magic Convention
which is a clothing conventionand Hustler was launching
their clothing andHustler had chosen me
to be the model of theirclothing and they made,
you know, picturesof me modeling it.
So I really didn'tthink about life after porn
because I justcouldn't believe how like,
all these thingskept happening.
I mean just the things thathappened to me as a new girl
in porn don't happen tomost new girls I mean,
I met Larry Flint um,
pretty much my secondmonth in the business.
So I didn't thinkabout life after.
I just said--I just always said
I'm gonna get marriedand have kids.
I used to sayby twenty-seven.
Now I say I wanna getmarried by thirty
and have kidsby thirty-two.
When I was marriedI only did girl-girl.
I left my husbandand did boy-girl.
Um, when I got back withmy husband at kickass
I only did girl-girlagain, we split up,
I did boy-girl, heh!
Then I took like a hiatusfor about six-seven months
and didn't shoot anything.
And that's whenI met this guy,
um, who's my, ended upbecoming my fiance,
but we were dating, andI didn't do boy-girl
when I was with him forthe first six months,
and then he was like, don'tyou think you should go
get a new porn contractbecause that's extra income
we can have every month.
And I was like well,you want me to have sex
with other guys?
And he was like well, it'sonly six times a year
you're gonna do it, andit's with a condom.
I was like okay.
Then of course, like, twodays before the movie
my ex was like, I don't want youhaving sex with other guys.
Arrrrg! Arr!
Let go of me!
Your derrière may be pretty,but that don't mean
it's bull-worked from apromiscuous lashing.
SLAP!
Ow!
♪
Every two-and-a-halfmonths I'd have to shoot
a boy-girl scene and er-usually about two days before
he would start beingreally mean to me,
and calling me names, eventhough he was the one
who wanted meto do the movies.
Then, on the day when I'dgo to shoot the movie
he'd go out with his friendsand get really drunk,
then he usually would notkiss me or anything
for two days later, thenwhen my check would come in
he's like that's my check, I letyou have sex with other people.
And then when I wouldbe asleep sometimes,
I'd be asleep and I'dhear him watching my movies.
He'd go and putit in like slow motion
and make sure theguy wore a condom
and I wasn'tlying about it.
Um, let's see.
The most I ever made in amonth was probably when
I was running for governorbecause my website
was making aroundtwenty-thousand a month
and then my online storeselling t-shirts and buttons
made about ten-fifteenthousand a month,
and, I felt really badcause I didn't have time
to mail'em all outso I just ended up
not mailing peopletheir orders.
I feel reallybad about that.
Um, and then my contractwas six thousand a month
and I was featuredancing, at that time
feature dancing usedto pay a lot more.
That was like, six thousandfor like, three weeks.
I dunno how much that is,
maybe like 50, 60thousand in a month.
That's probably the most.
And then I won a gameshow around that same time.
I won a game show Who Wants tobe Governor of California?
I won anothertwenty-one thousand.
Um, that was great.
Um, I guess the most inthe year would probably
be around 300 thousand.
I mean I don't think Ithought I was set for life
I always used to jokewith everyone that um,
I'm either going to, justmake a lot of money
or I might worst case scenarioI'll marry a rich person.
That's what I always said.
(nervous chuckling)
No one comesinto this business
to wanna be normal onthe back end of it.
Nobody thinksthat it's gonna end.
You jump on a merry-go-roundyou hope the ride never ends.
I don't think many of themcan spell the word future.
I don't think they did thisas a short term investment
in their own future,but they burned out.
Hookers are hookers.
I mean hookers are people whoare looking for a quick buck
with the least amount ofeffort so they turn tricks.
And, uh, being aporn star is just like,
uh, you know the, theworld's oldest profession
so, it's, it's notthat complicated,
uh, reality is hard.
A lot of people blame, blame theindustry for their problems
but, uh, then they get outin the real world and find,
lots of problemsin the real world too.
I grew up in Pensilvania, um,in the steel-mill towns.
Worked in thesteel-mills, I drove cabs,
it was sorta typicalthings, uh, people do.
There I did someillustrations for magazines,
in New York and eventually,started playing uh, music.
Did that for a while.
And then I cameout to California
and end up gettinginto dirty movies.
(laughing) Justmet some people.
Actually I was gonna doa uh, a photo spread,
I was gonna do somephotography of some girls
who were in the business.
I had an idea I would doa photo shoot of them
and thena little interview.
And, some people I knew fromillustrating magazines
in New York said yeah, we'llsee what you come up with,
if it's good we'll pay youand everything so I met the--
these two girls, and,before I knew it, uh,
I was, in themovies! (laughing)
So that's sortahow that started.
But you know when Iwas working it was,
it wasn't like itis today, it was,
I'd maybe work forty daysa year and maybe fifteen
to twenty dayswere sex days.
And today they workevery day of the week.
Maybe twice a day.
You know, viagra shootin' uptheir cocks and stuff like that
I mean it's just they'reruining their sex life
for the rest of theirlives, I'm telling ya!
I just think there'stoo much going on,
I mean just yourpersonal appetite of it.
I mean, if you'reworking as a performer
and you're working that much Imean, sex loses it'smystery
in it's sense and it's, I meanI remember being turned on
to a point some times,certain situations
where I wouldactually shake.
I mean I'm sure everybody'sbeen in that situation
and now that, I hateto see that go away.
I remember one time my dadpicked me up from the airport,
and I was coming in for theholidays and he's, and he-
I had, my pictures werein Hustler magazine eh,
they were on, about a movieand, and I think I was
(laughing) I was givingsome girl head!
And my father says, "I sawthat picture in Hustler."
I said uh, yeah, picture, that,wasn't so good of a picture.
And that's all wassaid! (laughing)
They never wa--It was not something
I wanted to expose themto because it wa--
you know it it, it'sembarrassing for them.
We were so proud of what wedid in some of these movies
we did that were-- that were,that got really big play,
that I actually tookher to screenings.
We had these screeningsin these theaters.
And I'm taking my wifethere watching me have sex
with these people.And, she was,
it was difficult for herbut, she appreciated
the work we were doing, butafter one or two times
it was like-- or wedid that, I said
hey we don'tdo this no more!
She didn't wanna see anypictures of me or anything.
Although she understoodwhat I was doing and knew
it was the thing that wasnot gonna be, a situation.
Can I ask you something?
Those cops, they'rehung pretty good, huh?
Bet they ain'tgot what I got.
Nobody's gotwhat I got.
So, yeah, I'd liketo retire and paint.
If I had a game plan.
I saved some moneybut I wasn't that good.
No...
I didn't make thatmuch money though.
Come on,what'd I make?
I mean I, didn'twork that much.
You talking aboutwhen you were acting?
Save money whenhe was acting?!
He just didn'thave any bills.
I didn't have any bills.See I told you
I didn't haveany bills--
And then he got me!Ha ha--
Then she showed up!
I'm a highmaintenance, baby.
Then she showed up...
Even if it's not particularlyglamourous that day,
you go to work andyou get fussed over,
and if it's a big enoughproduction there's
a makeup artist there, andthere's, and there's attention,
for people who likeattention, um,
and then they get paid!The very same day!
Woohoo!
Now, my great friendLee Carol once said
as long as you got a cunt,you'll never starve.
But, as a danger to that,because, it wears on your mind.
My parents didn't take, reallyan interest in my life
and I was also sexuallyabused at nine-years-old.
I had a teenaged boy and hissister who was my classmate
introduce me tosexuality and uh,
for the first time in mylife and it horrified me.
Yeah, as soon as Ibarely graduated high school,
which, I had tocheat my way through,
my dad ended up comingto me and saying listen,
you're outta the house, andliterally kicked me out
on the street withno food, no money.
And so I'm literallysitting out on the curb,
on Sherman Way, that bigtough rebellious teenager
was balling her eyes out.
And all of a sudden, thisum, beautiful black man
came over to me andsays, are you alright?
What's wrong, why areyou crying sweetheart?
"I have no moneyand I have no food
and my dad kicked me out."
He put his arm around meand I- I still to this day
can tell you what thatembrace felt like,
and he just saidbaby I can help you
and I thought Jesus hascome to rescue me.
You know I really thoughthe was gonna help me.
And he said there's a manin the apartment complex
who would love tomake love to you.
He lured me in.
I went--You mean have sex?!
He goes yes, buthe's really gentle,
really nice,and you'll get $35.
So, here I ama single mother,
I've doneprostitution and stripping,
now for sixyears I've had, uh,
I've been at gunpoint, I'vehad stalkers try and kill me,
cops try and bust me, I meanI've been in the mafia
basically for six years.
So, someone came to me says,girl, why don't you do porn?
I said porn? What's that?
It was a lot worse thanprostitution, like,
there's a wholecrew around,
they're all strokingthemselves going--
It was just totally degradingand I went oh my gosh
this is bad,this is really bad.
And then all ofa sudden like,
I can't explain it but allthe rage I ever felt from,
what my parents did, fromchildhood, from like,
all the things that men abusedme with in prostitution
I just like, let itout, on the screen.
He just said roll it and it'slike here I am the newbie
but I like, took over theentire scene, it was weird.
I just went-Rrrraw!
I'm Roxy! The porn star!Like I was pissed!
But at the end of the sceneit just ended and I had um,
bodily fluids on my face,and they just kinda went
here's a rag and theyjust threw it and me
and I just grabbedthe rag and went.
And I didn't wantthem to see me cry,
so I just kinda turnedmy face and I was like,
oh my god, oh my god,oh my god, don't cry,
Shelley, don't cry,don't cry, don't cry.
Then now all of a sudden I'minvolved doing like anal, um,
gang-bangs with five orsix different performers
and I'm thinkingoh my god.
Now I'm bringingbig jugs of vodka!
And everyone's eggingyou on telling you
no, girl we love you,we're your family now,
you're awesome, andthen, and there is
a family atmospherethat they offer.
Porn star karaoke,everybody hangs out
at the same parties,wooooo!
Girl, I love you!
Everyone's very affectionate,and the reason why
they're so affectionate isbecause that's their family.
Um, they're out, especiallyin my day, we're outcasts.
In fact I still havescars from suicide attempts.
And I--
I said I don't care, Idon't wanna live anymore.
And I took like thirtyprescription pills, and uh,
I didn't die, but I knewI wanted out, bad,
and I remember cryingto God,
drunk off my asson Jack Daniels,
thinking if you get meoutta this I'll serve you
with my whole life, I swear togod I'll do whatever you want!
Just get me outta this.
I mean, people whoare well adjusted
and have good life skillsand who are doing something
meaningful and constructivewith their lives,
they're not in theindustry to begin with so,
the people who are in theindustry are really broken
twisted souls withouta lot of great job skills
and uh, you know they'returbulent souls.
So, they'realways gonna be
twisting and turningin the wind.
We'd spent a lotof time in church.
I actually convinced my mom tosend me to Christian School
when I was 14, she found a wayto gather up the funds,
and I went and I was veryinvolved in my church,
without her.
You know,it was just, it was me
and my friendsand that was how
I grew upand you know,
that all changedwhen I was sixteen.
(laughing)
I spent the nightat a girlfriend's house,
and she, was a teenagedmom, and married,
and her husband,drugged me. With acid.
And I--At that time I had,
I hadn't even stayedup past ten.
So, uh, I didn't, I wasn'treally well versed
in the drug world.
And that changedeverything for me.
I did the best I couldto graduate high school
as fast as I couldand, and move out.
I was outta thehouse by seventeen.
I knew some people inthe adult industry
and I hung out with them and I'mstill friends with themnow,
I don't blame themfor hanging out with me
when I was young causethey were young too, so--
(laughing)
Met a few porn stars,and, just--
Fell in lovewith them.
I hung out with themuntil I was over eighteen,
did my first movie,and, you know,
it was onfrom there.
Well, the first year that Iwas in the adult industry,
and was doing movies Iworked for every company
under the sun.
You know the dirtiest of thedirtiest kinds of companies,
that do crazy stuff.
I worked for anybody, Icould, to make a buck.
I told my momand she flipped out.
She wasn't happy aboutit but eventually when I,
you know, formed a career,and I signed with Vivid,
and the pictureswere prettier,
and the footage was lessdisgusting, ha ha ha ha!
Um, she came to terms and youknow, what's she gonna do?
It is what it is.
Being a Vividgirl is, you know,
it's what every adult industryactress wants to be.
You know Vivid'sthe biggest best
and most well-knowncompany in the world.
They have the mostbeautiful girls,
they have thebest photographers.
Um, they havethe best press.
And, (deep breath),it's yeah, it's,
it's a high classslew of girls.
I would think-- I mean,of course you know,
it's as high classas it's gonna get.
(laughing)
Um, it's a steady income,so I don't know if
I necessarily thought I wasbetter than anybody else,
but I knew I was gettingthe press that I wanted,
so, I was happy.You know.
I took my moviesvery seriously.
I studied my scripts.
Half the timeI wasn't stoned,
when I did the dialogue,but I took my acting
very seriously becauseit was the only time
I was ever gonna getto do any acting.
So, I took it seriously!And I loved it!
And um, I thought I wasgood at it but, you know--
It just sounds socliche for me to say
I took the acting in myporno movie seriously.
But, but I did.
And that was my favoritepart, was the acting.
And sometimesthe sex.
(laughing)
You can use drugs andparty and drink,
no matter what careerchoice you have, but,
(deep breath), yes,you're opened up
to the party lifestylea lot more.
I mean, you hang outwith rockstars, you,
you know there's alwaysporn parties to go to, um--
Me, struggling as an addict,of course took advantage
of everything thatwas there, you know,
all of the alcohol,all of--
all of the drugs,I did 'em all!
(laughing)
Um--
It's not a safe businessto be in
if you wannastay clean.
It's not safe.
Um, and I'm nottelling you this
to make you feel sorryfor me or anything
but I had an extremelytough childhood,
and um, I think I got verylost for many years.
Um, I didn't know who Iwas, like many people.
Um, I had a very warpedunderstanding of what love was.
And um, I think because of alack of love in my life ora,
an inability to determinewhat love really is
I saw sexualattention, as love.
And when you've suffered a lotof sexual abuse in yourlife
it's understandable I thinkwhy you would feel that way.
Trying to tell you...
at what pointI made the decision
to be Tiffany Million is notsomething I could answer
really in justone neat sentence.
It's kind of acombination of things.
Essentially the whole reasonthat I even got into
that business to beginwith was because I was
a single mother, likemany people, and um,
I was living in SouthernCalifornia, I had no family,
I didn't knowthat many people,
her father wasn'thelping me with her,
and it was pretty scary beinga single parent honestly,
and so, I mean Ifigured, you know
I had a choice: I couldwork eight hours a day,
and commute an hour or twoeach way on the freeway,
to make, seveneight dollars an hour,
only to pay outhalf of that in taxes,
and child care, and mydaughter's with you know
heaven knows whoduring the day,
or I could re-enter theadult entertainment industry
'cause I'd been astripper years before.
And then I thought, causeI'd always been kind of a fan
of adult films, and I'd somany times I had looked
at those movies anduh, I'd thought man,
you know what I could do thatand I could do it better.
You know. And so I thoughtwell heck, why not?
I mean I didn't have aman in my life anymore,
I left her father, and uh, Idefinitely needed the money,
but really it justafforded me a way to,
work as little as possible toget as much money as I could
to be with my daughtercause that's all
I really wanted I wanted mydaughter to have a greatlife,
and a safe home, in agood neighborhood,
with good childcare,and I wanted
to spend as much timewith her as I could.
And working in the adultfilm industry allowed me
to work a day or two a weekand be with my daughter
the rest of the weekand make more money
than people thanworked, you know,
five days a week,eight hours a day.
What you do in pornfilms is not sex.
I mean I knowyou're being penetrated,
but it's like this,you know.
It's like this.
I mean that'swhat it feels like.
It's just something occupyingum, a chasm in your body.
Really--It's like this.
It's like this that'swhat it might as well be.
Uh, there uh,there's no emotion there,
there's nofeeling, um, you know,
you know, I gotta tell youthis funny little story!
I would have so manyfans come up to me
at autograph signingswhatever and tell me that
I was their favoriteporn star,
because all the othergirls were faking it
and I was the onethat they knew,
man, that I was forreal. (laughing)
And uh, and I can tellwhen a woman's faking it
and I'd be laughing!
Watch my face.Watch my face.
(screaming)
'Cause I'd be like--
I'm the biggest damnfaker you ever met!
I mean I'm good, that's whyI get paid the big bucks.
Even when I wasin the business,
I didn't partake of all ofthe extraneous activities.
Um, I think I went toseveral parties only
because there was freefood and boozes,
and I would go and Iwould eat and stuff
and then everybody wouldgo to the after-parties
and I'd be like nah, I'mgoing home and going to bed.
(laughing)
I've always been earlyto bed, early to rise.
I never wanted to be apart of that scene and um,
even when I wasworking in the movies
I always kinda felt likea fly on the wall.
Like I know mybody was involved,
because,obviously, I was there.
But I always had thisstrange feeling
this real feelingof disconnect.
Like I was uphere looking down.
When my father died in94, uh like I said
he left me a wholebunch of money,
and I suddenly realizedthat I'm free.
I don't have tobe her anymore.
And I walked away.And that was it.
No one puts a gun toanybody's head to do this.
If you're not warnedabout what's gonna happen
then the person who didn'twarn you is the person who's
guilty in that respect,but they're doing it
for the one thing thatthey cannot deny.
That absolute death-wish,for the recognition,
validation, andcredibility.
And they're welcome toit, but eventually
their past will catch upto them and they have
to be aware of the factthat X is forever.
When I got into the business,um, I, did have a goal.
It was my "crackedout" goal. (laughing)
But I did have agoal to, be out,
and retired, twenty-six, atthe latest twenty-seven.
Um--
And I was out,by twenty-four.
I didn't leave the businessbecause uh, I wanted to.
I left the businesscause I felt I HAD to.
That it was theright thing to do.
On November fourth, 1984,was the first headline,
in the SanFrancisco Chronicle,
regarding the heterosexualtransmission of AIDS.
A good friend of mine,who was a mathematician
had read the same articleI did and he came over
to my house in theafternoon and he said
"I've done some calculationsbased on the numbers,
reported here in the story.
And you're in the wrongplace at the wrong time.
I want you to stop."
I had three jobslined up for December,
my wife said I don'twant you to do them.
And my thinking was look,they're just trying
to sell newspapers, that'swhat newspapers do,
they scare you, and so I don'tthink the danger is
that real, and I'm gonna goahead and do these jobs.
So I went off andI did the three jobs.
And when I came home,and we're about to go
to bed, that night,she said to me
"Do you think we should?"
Should? Should what?Have sex?
"Yeah, do you thinkwe should have sex?"
And I said, what areyou talking about?
And she said, and Ican quote you verbatim,
I rememberedthis all this time.
She said "Don't youthink it would be prudent,
if one of us remainedalive, to raise the kids?"
Pchew!
That was the brick wall.
Somebody had offered mea DVD deal, and I--
I knew CD-ROMSdidn't do good,
I knew the laserdisks didn't do good,
and I thought,uh, this DVD thing,
whatever it is, won't replacevideo, so I signed it
without having a lawyerlook at it or anything,
and by the time DVDs startedtaking over from videos,
I looked at the contractand found out now
they have my DVD rights,also had internet rights,
and the companywasn't very good.
And once I realized I wasn'tgonna make much money
I stayed with EvilAngel my distributor,
for as long as I could,then when they stopped
doing videos that was it.
The ones that do well, are outbecause they wanna be out,
not because theyhad to get out.
And, they have madetheir peace with what they did,
and that showsin their bearing,
and the way thatthey are, in the world.
The money that I didsave up went really quick.
Um, and then I wasjust, scraping by.
And it was, um, it was theChristian community that
really came alongsideme and helped me out.
There would betimes when I was,
didn't know how Iwas gonna pay my rent,
and, somebody, it was justpeople I don't even know,
just people who've read mystory, who wanted to help.
When I left the businessI sold my house
in Los Angeles, um, I first-I retired, and then,
um, I decided, I needto get out of L.A.
I neededto get out of L.A.
I mean, everywhere Iwent, McDonalds drive-thru,
um, nightclubs, the movietheatre, the park,
Universal Studios,I mean, you name it,
I could not, go anywhere.I mean I don't know
how these big celebritiesdeal with it all.
I mean they must ha--
They have to havebodyguards of course
and stuff like that causeI did not have bodyguards
and I could nothandle it.
It's impossible to lead a normallife after you get out of it.
This is forever. Thisis the scarlet letter.
And it, it never goes away,you'll be dealing with the,
with the implicationsof this forever.
What, (sigh),
what tends to happen isthat it isolates you.
And so you,develop a, a fear of,
being rejected againand again and again
and so you put up wallsbetween you and other people,
and you isolate yourself andyou don't join communities,
and, when you're isolatedyou're less likely
to suffer rejection.
But you're also isolatedand living on the edge
so, um, you can neverget away from this,
there's no solution.
To go from beinguh, a movie star,
to zippothe pinhead overnight,
was just like,devastating to my ego.
If you're looking for a longcareer in the porn business
you're probablylooking in the wrong place.
Uh, the average girl, mightbe good for, two years?
Two to three years topsfor the average girl.
If you're lucky and you'reone of the few superstars,
not very many of those,okay then you get uh,
you know, six sevenyears. Eight years.
And if you playyour cards right,
and do your financial thingright, then you can,
you know, make some moneyand set yourself up.
Overall I guessI'm happy I did it.
I mean the only thing Idon't like is that, it,
the main thing I reallywanted to do is act and be
in comedies and tv, and Ifeel like it holds me back.
But I don't know if Iwould have just stuck
with the normal routeif I would've uh,
ended up makingit to tv at all,
who knows I'd probably,maybe still be
in Florida goingto castings,
maybe I never wouldhave come out here.
So, and I've gotten to doa lot of Cinemax movies
which are really fun too,and all those things
I've gotten to do becauseof probably the porn.
So overall I guessI'm happy I did it.
Um, uh, part of the reasonwe're her in Utah is
because porn isillegal here, so uh,
it really helps keep mefrom being recognized.
That and the fortyextra pounds I gained!
But um, now that I'mlosing that weight, um,
well I also cut off myhair so that helps too.
But um.
Yeah, everyone'sbeen really cool about,
um, if theyfind out who I am.
They've beenreally good about it.
When I took Kattyto her new daycare
and they asked, if I had um,reference names for like,
who to call if somethinghappens to Katty I said
I don't know anybody here, Ihave no references, sorry,
and she thought that wasa little bit suspicious,
and so shelooked me up online,
I had given her thename Asia Lemon, um,
and from that name shemanaged to figure out
who I was and so thenext day she goes,
uh, you know I did alittle Googling on you.
And I was like Ugh!(nervous laughing)
Miss Mormon Mommy of four whodid a little Googling on Asia.
I was like, so, youstill gonna watch my kid?
Well you know,unfortunately like uh,
one of the reasons I like--the fact that Vince Neal
has me playing his charitytournament for his daughter
for children'scancer and stuff,
and I played inthe Country uh,
Academy of Country MusicAwards charity tournament
this year and a few othercharity tournaments
cause it's one of the only ways,that porn people can give
to charities, unfortunatelyin this hypocritical world,
a lot of charities don'twant to accept money
from people that arein the sex business.
"Eww, the sexbusiness we can't do that."
Politicians,on the other hand,
who make us lookclean as hell,
no problemtaking their money.
Uh, unscrupulousbusiness men
who's ripping everybodyoff, no problem!
But because we have alittle sex once in a while,
naw, can't do you andthat pissed me off.
I had one interestingmoment in baseball
with my son in little league.
I had told nobodyabout my career,
and uh, one day the manager,who was this big black guy
who was a Stanford graduate,he comes up to me
and he goes, "Gonna besome trouble today."
And I said what do you mean?
He says, "One of the mothersknows who's you are."
He looks at me and he'ssays "You know I knew
who you were the minuteyou came on the field."
And he said I'lltell you the truth.
He said "Anybody that's been
in Nina Hartly's bootyis okay with me."
(laughing) He says
"I will take care of this."And he did.
MENSA'sa high IQ society.
You have to have an IQ in thetop two percent, to get in.
I got in, with a notarizedcopy of my SAT scores.
MENSA didn't want link tomy website even though
they linked all themember's websites,
because uh, of who Iwas, and adult star,
um, so, thatwas their excuse,
and so I made them a speciallittle webpage of Asia
just like, happy Asia, collegepictures and smiling Asia
and, just innocentstuff and it's two pages,
and that's, so that'swhere MENSA links to now,
instead of my regular site.
And they finallyacknowledged me
in their MENSA celebrityissue which was,
a really big moment for me.That was cool.
Wait,how do you say it?
(inaudible)Unprecedented?
Unprecedented?It sounds weird.
Okay. (laughing)
I've done somethingunprecedented that
nobody else in, the adultindustry has ever done.
Um, and that wasyou know running
for Governor of California,actually two times.
And um, it was amazing,when I first started out,
the owner of my companyand I thought that
it was gonna be justlike a little fun joke,
see if I couldget some press,
maybe get on the van.com,so when I went down
to the courthouse to getmy paperwork when we said
I was gonna do it, um,Howard Stern Show
sent a camera crew down,Channel 7, Channel 5,
all the newsshows showed up,
Associated Press, writers,and that's when him
and I are like Okay,I gotta get on that ballot
because this isgonna be huge.
I'm going to get ridof the car tax and
put a tax on breastimplants instead.
I will legalizegay marriage.
And I will make sureeveryone who files
for unemploymentgets jury duty.
In other words, California,I'll be a kickass governor,
so vote for me, MaryCarey, on October 7th.
I mean, of course, someof my platforms were very
tongue in cheek, andfunny but, you know,
when I was gettingtowards the end of it
I realized that youknow I really wanted
to make a difference andI felt like I really was
making a difference becauseI was getting a lot
of people who normallywouldn't follow politics
to follow, because of me.And um, you know,
and then I was likewhat if I win?
(laughing) But, you know,
coming in tenth placeis pretty amazing
out of a hundred andthirty-two people.
When I was eighteenyears old, um,
I went to uh, real-estateschool, just everything
about real-estatejust I really liked,
so I figured that I wouldalways, do something withthat.
I was working fora builder, uh, a,
a home builder, here,and, corporate,
came to my communityand shut the doors
and said we needto talk to you.
Someone recognized you,We know who you are,
and you are toorecognizable and it's a,
we're tooconservative of a company,
and we're gonnahave to let you go.
And so that wasright before,
that was a week before Igot diagnosed with cancer.
And the ones that gotout of this business
and now are being blightedby the society that
jacked off to them.
Well the society are theones that's guilty for that.
They're damning themfor something that
gave them pleasure,but they refuse
to admit that they gotthe pleasure from them.
and that's a very verysad state of affairs.
Now I wasstarting to direct,
and I was hired, uh,a couple months later,
to go to Germany to work.
I'd make about eight grandor something like that.
Work eight daysor something.
And I didn't wanna dothis any more at this time,
I didn't wannado it any more.
So I left, said goodbyeto her, stood in line
two hours, and as I'm goingI'm saying I don't wanna go,
I'm saying to myselfI don't wanna go,
I don't wanna go,I don't wanna--
And it just built upand built up until I got,
finally got tothe point of where,
"May I help you?"
they said, youknow, ticket counter,
I said uh, no,I'm not going.
(laughing) I took mybags, I call up Kathleen
and I said babyI'm coming home,
I don't wanna go, I don'twanna go to Europe.
I'm thinking about thetrip and everything,
I don't wanna do this, Iwanna stay home with her.
So, that was prettymuch the last thing I did.
Really what got meout of it was my husband.
Because, when I metRon, he had no idea
who I used to be.Ron loved me, for me.
And you know he couldhad a much younger woman,
he could had a muchbetter looking woman,
he could had a womanwith a lot more money.
But he fell in lovewith me.
He didn't know anythingabout that part of me.
And the fact that heaccepted me for who I was
and loved mefor who I was--
Taught me howto love me.
Really.
And his love for mehas reconnected me
with the person thatI was before I EVER,
did any of this crap.
All of a sudden Mr. Right cameinto my life, and I hated him.
Ha! When I first met him.
His whole life he wasraised in Christian school
from like, he went to thesame school, the same kids
from like kindergartento like twelfth grade.
He was like most valuableplayer, he did sports,
his mom hadall these trophies.
She hasa book this thick
just on newspaperclippings on him.
So I was like jealousalready I hated his guts.
He would like knock on mydoor and I would answer
and go,what do you want?
and he goes "I'm hereto clean your house."
And I'd be like,what are you doing?
He goes "You're filthy."
Ha!
Like, cause I didn'tcook, and I didn't clean
and I was, and I was,I was falling apart.
So he literallycleaned my whole house.
With rags for me, and um,I just stopped working.
didn't wanna prostituteanymore and lie anymore
and we just hit it off andthe next thing you know
we're snorting meth, andnext thing you know
we're reading thebible together.
And we're like(sniff) dude!
Did you see like how likeGod used Joshua like
to conquer allthose cities dude.
And he'd be like(sniff) yeah and (inaudible)--
and like I, I mean we're werejust like so into the Bible!
And we realized that he hadwent to Christian school
his whole life and was thepastor's son so he had
a really great Christianfoundation and,
I didn't as much as himbut, he was so sweet
and he never once pursuedme sexually, so, um,
we ended up getting marriedon Valentine's Day, 1995.
I met my husband in a pool,in Hollywood, Florida.
At the Diplomat Hotel.And he was married
at the time and I had aboyfriend at the time.
And, he was in themiddle of splitting up
and I was kindadone with it.
Little Trist.
And, I told him I wasin the middle of uh,
putting a webpage together,and, he said oh okay,
and, it had to be maybethree months after
I got my first website up thatI got an email from him.
We went out once,that was it.
We haven'tbeen apart since.
Um, my husband diedin a car accident
driving homefrom Las Vegas.
I had asked him not to dothis whole gig actually,
um, I waseight months pregnant
and I didn't want himaway from me that long,
and uh, he's like"I gotta do it honey",
but he tried, he cutit down to two days
so he was really happy cominghome on the second day
that he wasall done with this
and he came racing hometo be with his pregnant wife
and he flipped the jeep anddidn't ever make it home.
Suddenly he's goneand now here I am,
no more income andall these bills to pay
and it was just like onething on top of another.
And so I, I just, I putup a plea on my website
asking, uh, for donations.
I didn't knowwhat else to do.
No insurance,no money, bills,
and my fans donated,enormous amounts of money.
Um, the kids werecompletely spoiled,
they got toys andbooks and presents
and stuff with pictureson it and just it was,
unbelievable it wouldmake me cry all the time
I would open all the mailfrom all these people
I'd never met and itwas just, it was
really wonderful havingfans turn out to help me.
Because you know, I'dbeen online for ten years,
they'd watched grow upand I'd never asked
for anything before andhere I was I needed help.
And they helped me.
I faced those up and,up and downs many times.
Certainly with myreal-estate practice
and the market and when themarket dropped in real-estate,
and now that themarket and, you know,
is dropping all theway across the board
I mean the countryis in crisis.
Our wholecountry is in crisis.
It would be reallyeasy for me right now,
to want to reinvestigate,you know, porn.
I definitelywanna have kids.
That's something like, Iwas actually very depressed
recently because I,I'm realizing that
I'm twenty years oldand I'm not married
and I have no kids. AndI really want kids.
And, I'd like to have atleast two. Maybe three.
Because being an onlychild I always wished
I had a brother or sister.
I still wish I had abrother or sister.
Like, you know I just,that's something
I've always wanted so.
I have a gorgeous family.
My son is amazing.He's my angel.
My daughter is the best thingthat ever happened to me.
She saved my life.
I want my daughter to have acompletely different life.
I want her to, go tocollege is number one.
She's a greatstudent, she's a track star,
she's had to dealwith my porn life.
She, um, hates it.She's embarrassed of it.
And, um, she won't letme, she doesn't want me
to go to hertrack meets, sh--
because she feels someonewould recognize me.
We're going to church now,I go to church and I um,
have a strong faith, andI have changed my life
and I want for hereverything that--
I, I don't want her toever have to experience
what I experienced.
In the moment?Thank you!
For being who you are.
Cause you're apretty cool dude.
(laughing) Oooo!
Ooo, can I getthat in writing?!
Sure! I can give itto you in writing!
Um.
You're welcome.
It's interesting.
I mean, what I'm sittinghere thinking is, I wonder
how many other people outthere can have this kind
of conversation withtheir parents.
I mean most people can'tsit around and think
about their parentshaving sex, or, um,
especially fucking somebodyother than their mother.
I mean that alonewould I think
irritate a lotof children.
But, it's very, normalized,in that sex is
a goody thatshould be enjoyed.
Um, and when you candifferentiate between sex
and love and everythingthat happens in between,
um, it's a huge giftthat you can give yourself,
and lovers and partnersand friends and family.
And I'm grateful thatthat's, that's my world.
Wow.
I'm impressed.
She, is my role model.She is my hero.
And, I think Ilearned a lot from my mom.
She's gone through a lotand I even tell people that
she's my hero andshe's my role model.
She's just like whatever,I did it for my daughter
and now she's doing whatshe wants to she owns
her own business, and nomatter how many people
talk down about hershe's still does what
she wants to do andshe's successful at it.
So, I guess she'sjust a good example of,
don't let otherpeople bring you down,
just keep doingwhat you're doing
and you'll be successfulin what you wanna do.
So. I'm very proud of you!Just so you know that!
Please don't start cryingcause then I'll start crying!
I'm not gonna cry!
I will start crying.
And since my husbanddied there wasn't a lot
for me to look forward to so itwas kinda nice to have that.
Mom,your husband died?
(laughing) Daddy.Where's Daddy?
Where's Daddy?
Up in the clouds.
There comes a point in our lifewhen family becomes first,
the first thing and thequestion, the answer
to the question, it justdoesn't even take a beat.
Sometimes...(unintelligible)
And we have the opportunity tosee our friends andfamily.
I think Chuck wouldreally appreciate,
that we're here today.
There was something uniquelyvital about Buck Adams that
could brighten upthe darkest moment,
and put a grin on the faceof the bleakest situation.
With a body that appeared tobe hewn from a granite block
of cement, and an intensitythat provided his fans
with a vicarious sustenance,Buck Adams will always be
remembered as the guy whogot it up when it counted.
You know like I said, if youknew it was gonna happen...
what wouldyou have said?
And you don'talways get that chance.
Um, but right now,in my life,
I, regret doing porn.
I regret doing porn andI never thought, ever,
that I would be,who I became.
Houston.
I never thought I would beso big and so recognizable
and just, I justnever thought that
it would turn intowhat it did, for me.
And Godjust says, Shelley,
I'm telling you,you need to--
you need to trust me,
I've got something betterfor you. I love you.
I didn't save yourass all these years
not to give yousomething better.
Well, like,looking back, I didn't,
honestly I can't really likego, on my computer and,
and look at stuff thatI used to do anymore
it just makes me, Ijust, I'm so different.
I feel so different nowlike, where I am in life.
It's really hard for me tobelieve that I was that girl.
So yes, it has changed me.For the better I believe.
The porn businesshas afforded me
a very comfortable lifeit has allowed me
to educate myself in waysthat I probably wouldn't
have been ableto do before.
It's enabled me to travelall over the world and,
meet new andinteresting people.
And it's allowedme to, have the,
have the cajones,if you will,
to try new andexciting things that
I probably wouldn'thave done before.
I would havebeen afraid to do.
I have no fear,to do anything.
You know because aspeople we have to fully
and freely accept ourselffor everything we are
and everything we're notcause if we have compar--
If we compartmentalize,we're never a whole self.
You know. Especially inlike relationships,
we don't get tobring our whole self.
What I am afraid of the mostis because I've lasted
so long and this industryis now heading towards
its fourth decade ofpresence on this earth,
that the people whocreated this business,
the Eric Edwardses,the Jamie Guillesses,
the John Lesleys, the greatpioneers of this business,
are not gonna be withus, forever, and,
I'd hoped to be around longenough to honor them
but I don't wanna doit fast and furiously
because when they startto fall by the wayside
somebody's gonna haveto remember them.
It's based on a line that,"there is no future
if in the present we failto pay homage to the past."
But a lot of them are nowin their fifties andsixties,
some of them in theirseventies, and somebody is
going to have to be thereto tell their stories.
Eventually thiswoman is gonna like say,
wwheeeeuuuheehehehuh.
And then when you'reeighty-five and you can't
walk no more and you're in awheelchair she's gonna say
"You remember when youwanted to have sex all day?
Yeah, what do youmean, you want what?
Bap!
What do you want?Bap!
No no no, now I'mgetting back at you."
(chuckling)
I miss many thingsabout the business.
But, I guess the clearest wayto say it concisely would be,
the biblical phraseoccurs to me,
"when I was a childI spake as a child,
and when I was a man,I put away childish things."
I'm trying to thinkof like Joe Nameth.
Joe, do you missfootball?
Sure he does.
But he can't playlike he used to play.
He's, sixty-fiveyears old now.
I'm in the same place.
Am I happy I did porn?Uh, yeah,
I really don't have toomany regrets cause I,
it's so much stuff cameout of it that was positive.
I got to travel aroundthe world, uh,
I met a lot ofinteresting people,
I'm way over myquota sexually,
uh, I think uh,people ask me and I,
I guess the estimate's,I've been with like,
three-thousand womenor something like that,
most of them wereawesome to work with,
um, still friends witha lot of 'em, so uh,
yeah, overall it was ahell of an experience.
Essentially I am livingmy life right now
the way I wanna live itfor the rest of my life
and I wanna, I wanna die doingwhat I'm doing right now.
How many peoplecan say that?
Well I am, that I livehere and I have a place
that I love this muchI think I'm as lucky
as anybody could beon earth.
Far as, I mean, I dunnowhat the hell t'ask for.
I'm happy.
I'm notin a dark place,
I'm not suicidal,I'm not doing drugs.
You know I'm notself-destructive.
Um, but the last twoyears has been a journey,
cause I was veryself-destructive before and,
I'm not saying itchanged overnight,
I still haveself-destructive thoughts,
but, um, I'm just in an,healthier place all around.
You hear some people wetalk to who are leading
normal lives, and aredoing pretty good,
like how the hellwould you really know,
like, how would you knowwhat really goes on
in their life at two a.m.?
The torment, the, you know,how would you know that
they're gonna tell youabout all the times
they've been rejected andisolated and,
and the horror andthe shame that,
that their childrenconfront and that,
their spouses confront,and the shame that
they've put theirfamilies through and,
and the relationships thathave been permanently broken.
I mean all the, all theburned bridges behind them
because they'vedone sex work.
You know most familiesaren't proud
when their daughtersbecome hookers.
I think the difference betweenme and the other girls
in the industry wasthat I've really,
enjoyed being there andum, not just the sex
I mean I, used it to bettermyself as a person.
I never let the industry takeadvantage of me in anyway.
I always tookadvantage of the industry.
I made phenomenal amounts ofmoney I've produced movies,
I wrote movies,I starred in them,
hell people werepaying me hundreds
of dollars an hourto sign autographs?
Woo hoo! I'm up,I'm with this!
Um, I just, I- I ...
The other girls leave witha bad taste in their mouth
and they- and I just,I have nothing
but good memorieswhen I look back.
And right now if I wantedto go back into porn
I could probably go get acontract almost at any company
and still just do straightboy-girl scenes.
And if I really wantedto when I'm thirty-two
if I wanna go back to pornand because I'm really broke
maybe let's say,hopefully it won't happen,
I would tell a porncompany guess what,
I'm gonna come back anddo two guys and do anal.
If I'm thirty-five and reallypoor I need to do porn,
I'll tell 'em I'll do, youknow, a black guy. Heh!
There isn't thatmuch of a future
after the x-rated industrybecause somehow,
somewhere, somebodywill find you.
The famous line I usedto say to anybody
walking into my office whenI ran the biggest agency,
what are you gonna doten years from now
when your kid bringshome a magazine
with you laying inthe middle of it
with a candle shovedup your ass?
You gonna tell'emyou were playing
the partof a birthday cake?
It doesn't go away.
My husband and myson changed my life.
And my son saved my life.
(sigh) And lookingat him every day,
reminds me howprecious life is.
And how throwing itaway on drugs and alcohol,
just this stupidcrap that's out there,
god, it's just so notworth it. You know?
♪